Eric McElyea



Full Stack Developer

OWork/School Github

inLinkedin

☑ericmcelyea@gmail.com



Personal statement

Hi, I am Eric McElyea. I do full stack development. On a typical work day, you might find me doing front-end development in React or Angular, back-end work in NodeJS and Nginx, writing jasmine unit tests, setting up servers, improving automated build/test tools, or helping create and assign tasks for the next sprint. I understand and have worked on every part of a modern application stack, and can operate comfortably on any part with a knowledge of the whole.

Eric McElyea



Work Experience

Solo Developer

Doc Current

This is a side project I took from nothing to production

Came up with concept, tested feasibility of idea, designed UI/UX.

Built system for uploading, editing, signing, emailing, text messaging california rental property documents

Designed and Built ReactJS application

Built React component for auto-populating, editing, signing PDF based web forms

Built NodeJS backend, designed DB

Wrote NodeJS process that converts JSON and a blank PDF to a signed, filled PDF

Handled every aspect of application development, devops, security, etc.

December 2017 - current

Full Stack Developer

Parsley

Worked on Front-End React, Redux application

Worked on Back-End Scala, Play Framework, Postgres

Sept 2017 - Dec 2017

Full Stack Developer

Katalyst Fitness

Built front-end AngularJS application to design specs

Created scheduling system for employees, clients and studios

Created secure JWT user authorization system

Built PCI compliant credit card billing system

Created tools for automating test, build, and deploy process

Sep 2016 - Oct 2017

Software Engineer

Acutulus

Work with a variety of clients who hired the company to build their software:

Tapcast - wrote android plugins for cordova/phonegap application, redid website to spec whenever it was changed (which was fairly frequently).

Tavirecruiter - Built applicant tracking system for a recruiting company

Revbooks - Creates a book of online store products, I was the new guy so I had the unenviable task of pulling online store http routes and user validation out of sites so the book could spoof a user cart/checkout experience without ever visiting the site. This did teach me alot about web fundamentals and how to interface with a plethora of different back-ends, front-ends and engineering teams.

Jan 2015 - Oct 2017



Education

BSc in Computer Science

Cal State East Bay

Relevant coursework: Data Structures, Operating Systems, Systems Programming, OOP, Web Development, Mobile Development, Data Communications and Networks, Calculus 1, 2 & 3, Statistics, Discrete Math, Linear Algebra, have three GE classes left to finish degree, I enjoy working in industry far more but will force myself to do them someday.

2012 - 2014

Lower Division Classes

Diablo Valley College

I did not do a 4 year degree in 2 years. Did all my lower division classes here.

2008-2010



Technical skills

Angular

React

Nginx

NodeJs

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

Additionally, in support of these broader skills: express, npm, yarn, redux, gulp, grunt, webpack, es6, typescript, jasmine, sass, bootstrap, jwt, redis, aws, azure, docker, https, advanced terminal skills, and more.

66

Testimonials

Eric is a hard working engineer. He adapted to the company's style and workflow quickly, while mastering new frameworks and technologies. Eric is enthusiastic about projects, he remains focused and is able to prioritize. He continues to produce optimized, reusable code while learning whatever is needed to produce the best product. As a small company we all have to fill various roles and be able to work independently, Eric excels at this. Whether it is coding new applications from the ground up, debugging and optimizing existing code, or coordinating with customer engineering teams, he succeeds at the task at hand.

Ed Parsons

CEO Acutulus Enterprises